# **Prathima Bommannagari**









#### **CAREER PROFILE**

Dedicated Computer Science graduate student at the University of North Texas graduating in May 2023. Ten solid years of IT experience in the areas of Analysis, Design, and Development. Skilled at coding, programming, data structures, and algorithms.

# SKILLS

Software: Visual Studio | UML | Git | VMware Workstation | Microsoft Office Suite | Programming Languages: Java | Python | UNIX | C++ | Web Technologies: HTML5 | XML | CSS3 | Applets | Servlets | Java Script | jQuery | AJAX | Bootstrap | React JS | Redux Operating Systems: Windows | Linux | Database: Oracle, MySQL | Languages: English, Telugu, and Hindi – All professional proficiency or above

#### **EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE**

EdgeVerve Systems Limited, India

Aug 2015 - Jul 2021

## Role: Technology Analyst, Web Developer

- Collaborated on and utilized React JS, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS3, Sass, HTML5, jQuery, AJAX, and Java spring boot framework in the Finacle Core Banking web application project, which is used by banks across 100 countries and serves over 1.05 billion users.
- Led a team of 4 people in resolving UAT and Production issues of Finacle banking applications raised by Clients from the Middle East and Africa.
- Implemented SHA-256 algorithm for 'Hashing' to secure the credentials of the user on the network with Finacle Core banking application login.
- Wrote UNIX shell scripts to automate the data loads and expedited version migration.
- Engaged in DB validations for batch import data using PL/SQL, and DB Triggers.
- JSPs, Java Scripts, applets, and servlets were utilized to configure and modify the Single Sign-on framework, which applications in the Finacle Universal Banking Solution suite employ to authenticate users into the system at the server and browser level to fulfill business requirements.
- Actively involved in performing parallel tasks as part of the emergency and monthly releases in addition to efficiently handling of Signature Verification System issues to the customers.
- Full Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) experience including Analysis, Design, and Review of Business and Software Requirement Specifications; Development, Testing per Agile software development methodology.

Nov 2010 - Jul 2015 Infosys Limited, India

## Role: Systems Engineer, OBIEE Developer

- Handled design and implementation of dimensional models in the Repository of OBIEE built on the OLTP database.
- Performed extensively in BI and ETL-based data issues of ICICI bank and built reports using OBIEE 11g.
- Developed and deployed dashboards, analytics, and reports properly.
- Experienced in Enterprise Manager, BI Console, and Command Manager.
- Collaborated with business areas and data owners to successfully implement and maintain an enterprise-level business analytics and data warehousing solution.
- Conducted design and coding of the Extraction, Transformation, and Loading of ODS.
- Designed and implemented complex data structures, dashboards, and ad hoc reporting.

# **PROJECTS**

- Developed a web application to provide a platform for user-driven reviews and ratings on Movies and TV shows. |Tech Stack: HTM5L, CSS3, React JS, MySQL Database, and Java Spring Tool Suite
- Contributed to a Machine Learning project 'Coupon Purchase Prediction' to predict the coupons that will be purchased by users based on their browsing history and past purchasing habits. | Tech Stack: Python (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, and Scikit Learn)
- Collaborated in a team project 'Ransomware Creation and Mitigation' that includes ransomware creation, infection, monitoring, detection, and mitigation | Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Python
- Launched a portfolio website that details my work, skills, and experiences. | Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript
- Developed a Dice Roll Simulator program. | Tech Stack: Python (tKinter, and PIL)
- Implemented a Weather Application. | Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript
- Developed a Meme Generator Web Application. | Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, ReactJS
- Designed and implemented a Tenzi Game Web Application. | Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ReactJS

#### **EDUCATION**

University of North Texas | Denton, Texas, United States

Master of Science | Computer Science

Graduated May 2023 GPA: 4.0

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University | India Bachelor of Science | Computer Science Graduated May 2010

GPA: 3.7

### **LEADERSHIP & PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS**

# **UNT On-Campus Employment, Texas, United States**

May 2022 - July 2022

Role: STEM Student Employee

- Contributed my expertise as a Teaching Assistant on 'Web Accessibility' and 'Introduction to Artificial Intelligence' during a Summer Camp organized by Dr. Stephanie Ludi, Chair of the Computer Science department.
- Assisted students with autism disorder on various class projects regarding Artificial Intelligence and Web accessibility.

# Infosys Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR) Team, India

Mar 2018 – July 2021

Aims to reduce the damage caused by natural hazards like earthquakes, floods, and cyclones, through an ethic of prevention.

### AWARDS/SCHOLARSHIPS/GRANTS

Best Employee of the Month Award, EdgeVerve Systems Ltd. GEM (Going an Extra Mile) Award, Infosys Ltd.

September 2020, December 2017 February 2015